<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>pyqtgraph on Jean Bilheux</title>
    <link>/tags/pyqtgraph/</link>
    <description>Recent content in pyqtgraph on Jean Bilheux</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/pyqtgraph/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep Pan and Zoom of ImageView When Displaying New Image</title>
      <link>/post/pyqtgraph_states/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/pyqtgraph_states/</guid>
      <description>The ImageViewer of pyqtgraph is amazing but comes with an annoying feature, the reset of the pan and zoom if you display a new image (as shown here)
A couple of lines of codes need to be added in order to preserve those settings when switching image. Looks like nothing but it took me a couple of hours to figure it out so here it is with code before and after</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with the histogram widget of pyqtgraph</title>
      <link>/post/pyqtgraph_histogram/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/pyqtgraph_histogram/</guid>
      <description>The histogram tool on the side of the image coming for free with pyqtgraph is amazing. You can change or move the range but any refresh of the image reset the settings defined. Here is how you can fix those settings.
My main challenge has been to recover the id of the histogram when not initializing this one myself. And here is the way
class MyPyqt(QMainWindow): histogram_level = [] def __init__(self): self.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bragg Edge User Interface (iBeatles)</title>
      <link>/project/ibeatles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/ibeatles/</guid>
      <description>Several wavelength-dependent proof-of-concept imaging measurements have been performed at the Spallation Neutron Source (SNS) VULCAN and SNAP beam lines. This effort is focused on prototyping imaging software for the future SNS VENUS imaging beam line. One of the time- of-flight (TOF) techniques that is of interest to the scientific community is the 2-dimensional mapping of phases and average crystalline plane orientation in samples ex-situ, but also during applied stresses such as tensile loading and heating.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>