<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Jean Bilheux</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Jean Bilheux</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>QTableWidget (with 3 rows of headers) and Tree interacting together</title>
      <link>/project/table_and_tree_prototype/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/table_and_tree_prototype/</guid>
      <description>For one of my projects, I needed to answer the following requirements:
 table with 3 rows of labels (each row of label is a submenu of the row above) resizing any of the column will resize accordingly the other rows scroll of any of the label rows will scroll the other labels tree on the size will allow to hide/show any of the column hidding any of the tree should automatically hide the leaves under it if hidding all the leaves of a branch, automatically hide the branch parent user should have the option to save and reload a configuration full reset of table is available user can remove configurations he created  Because QTableWidget does not allow several rows of label, I had to built this feature from scratch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neutron Imaging Official Web Site</title>
      <link>/project/neutron_imaging_web_site/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/neutron_imaging_web_site/</guid>
      <description>Using HUGO framework, I implemented the Oak Ridge National Laboratory Neutron Imaging Web Site.
Why? Being granted beam time at our beam lines can be intimidating as they are many steps that have to be completed before coming to the facility. We used to try to answer those questions by email. This present some issues: * easy to miss some steps * previous users coming to the beamline hesitate in contacting us again * information we send can easily be out of date</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bragg Edge User Interface (iBeatles)</title>
      <link>/project/ibeatles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/ibeatles/</guid>
      <description>Several wavelength-dependent proof-of-concept imaging measurements have been performed at the Spallation Neutron Source (SNS) VULCAN and SNAP beam lines. This effort is focused on prototyping imaging software for the future SNS VENUS imaging beam line. One of the time- of-flight (TOF) techniques that is of interest to the scientific community is the 2-dimensional mapping of phases and average crystalline plane orientation in samples ex-situ, but also during applied stresses such as tensile loading and heating.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jupyter notebooks</title>
      <link>/project/jupyter_notebooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/jupyter_notebooks/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>